WAYNF TIPTON

PROFILE

I'm driven by turning ideas into reality. Web development has never been "just a job" for me. What started as a simple "Hello World" program has become a full-fledged passion that gets more exciting with each new experience.

I'm a web developer because I love the unique blend of problem-solving, technology, creativity, and communication that's essential to producing something meaningful.

CONTACT

PHONE: 469-274-0250

WEBSITE: https://waynetipton.com

EMAIL: wayne.tipton@gmail.com

HOBBIES

Programming **Blues Guitar BBQ** Grilling Chess Public Speaking

Web Developer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Frontend Web Developer at Accurate Digital Marketing Feb 2018 - Present

Re-designed WordPress website improving Google mobile speed score from 56 to 95.

2 Developed React single page landing pages for Google Ads campaigns generating 8% CTR.

☆ Developed conceptual designs for clients winning over \$8,258 of monthly business.

☆Remediated various website performance issues and client inquiries in a timely manner.

2nd VP Systems Administrator at Northern Trust

Oct 2006 - March 2018

- ✔ Regional project manager delivered \$15MM virtual computing platform on time and under budget.
- ✓ VMWare vCenter & vSphere virtual machine administration with 98% "first touch" resolution score.
- ✓ 8.67% network performance improvement as project lead on WAN Installation initiative.
- ✓ Garnered Technology Quality Medallion for outstanding service.

EDUCATION

Boston University Metropolitan College MS Data Analytics

2015 - 2017

University of Phoenix BS Information Technology 2002 - 2004

MILITARY

United States Navy

Petty Officer 2nd Class Electronics Technician

SKILLS

Technology

React JS Redux JavaScript ES 6 HTML 5 CSS 3 Bootstrap Photo and video editing

Soft Skills

Leadership and communication Technology problem solving Public Speaking Analytical/quantitative skills Written communication Interpersonal/teamwork skills